Nguyen Quoc Tuan - Network Security

Quang Nam, Vietnam



nguyenquoctuan2051.work@gmail.com



0363282235

Summary

I just graduated with a Bachelor of Cybersecurity and have 10 months of experience working in many network infrastructures and systems. I went through school subjects like network design management, penetration testing, and defense processes. My goal is to become an administrator, monitor the network and system

Experience



Network Engineer

Tedev

Jun 2023 - Present (5 months)

- Support Deploy and Operate TedevACS for Mobifone:
- + Description: Wifi device management web app(Auto Configuration Server)
- + Technology using: NodeJS(npm, yarn), MongoDB, Docker, Github, Ubuntu Server.
- + Responsibilities:
 - Support edit Front-end code to fix UI product error.
 - Deploy product with npm, yarn/Docker(using Dockerfile to build, save, load and run Image)
 - Support Mobifone to Operate TedevACS Server(using Ubuntu Server to checkport(netstat, netcat), tracelog, manage service running).
 - Find, Import and Export data from MongoDB on Ubuntu.
 - Research documents of TR-069(CWMP) to configure for new Wifi devices.
- Support Network optimization for Mobifone:
- + Description: Optimization for Metro Networks of Mobifone
 - Using protocols(CDP, NTP, IP Loopback, Neighbor) to check Routers on Rings of Metro Networks.
 - Reseach and Practice about protocol(CDP, NTP, SNMP), Routing(OSPF: Link-state, LSA, OSPF Database, Network Type)
 - Support upgrade JunOS for Juniper device of Metro Network Mobifone.

Network Administrator

VNNIC

Feb 2023 - Apr 2023 (3 months)

Student Internship

- Deploy Network Infratructure 3 Layer for Enterprise.
- + Description: Deploy Network Topology on Lab(https://tinyurl.com/Labvnnic).
- + Technology using: Firewall ASA, HA, STP, VRRP, DHCP, LCAP, iBGP...
- + Responsibilities:
 - Configure basic Firewall ASA(Sub-interface, Trunking and DHCP for Vlan, HA Failover, Default Route, Policy(ICMP))
 - Support teammate to configure VRRP, STP, Port-Security.
 - IP planning for network topology.
- Trained in basic knowledge of overview about Routing (OSPF, BGP), IPv6.

💯 Information Technology Help Desk

FPT Software

Nov 2022 - Jan 2023 (3 months)

Student Internship

- Support technical for end users.
- Setup OS(domain, license, firmware, proxy).
- Setup and recall hardware for end users.

Education

Duy Tan University

Bachelor's degree - Cyber Security of CMU Program

Aug 2019 - Jun 2023

Capstone Project 1: Penetration Testing IDOR(Burpsuit)

Capstone Project 2: C2 Attack and Automatic Log analysis(Splunk, VT4, SOAR Splunk)

(https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=r6fr8fDZO5Q)

Skills

- Network Administration(Routing(OSPF, Static Routing, RIPv2), Switching(Vlan, VTP, Trunking, STP)
- Service Desk(Support setup OS, fix driver, error application)
- English(Intermediate English Communication)
- · Internet Protocol (IP)(IP planning, IP class)
- · OSI Model
- Ubuntu(Checkport, service, log)
- · Windows Server (Deploy DNS, DHCP, Web Server on Lab)

Licenses & Certifications

- Certified AppSec Practitioner (CAP) The SecOps Group
- Linux System Administration with IBM Power Systems Coursera
- Fortinet Certified Associate CyberSecurity